<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>The Arts in Happy Valley</title>
<link>https://happy-valley-arts.com/blog.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://happy-valley-arts.com/blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>A blog dedicated to the arts in Happy Valley, Pennsylvania.</description>
<generator>quarto-1.5.55</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 04:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Panna Fresca at the Zoller Gallery</title>
  <dc:creator>Andrew Ferguson</dc:creator>
  <link>https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/sept12_24/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<section id="panna-fresca-new-visual-arts-faculty-show" class="level1">
<h1>Panna Fresca | New Visual Arts Faculty Show</h1>
<p>Panna Fresca, translated from Italian, means “Fresh Cream.” An apt name for the School of Visual Arts’ new faculty display at Penn State. Located in the <a href="https://arts.psu.edu/facilities/zoller-gallery/">Edwin W. Zoller Gallery</a>, this exhibit highlighted selected works by new faculty in the School of Visual Arts. Featured faculty artists are:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://michelleinezhinojosa.com/">Michelle Hinjosa</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.austincaskie.com/">Austin Caskie</a></li>
<li><a href="https://atencahb.art/">Beatrice Atencah</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.ditianarts.com/">Di Tian</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.kumasijbarnett.com/">Kumasi Barnett</a></li>
</ul>
<section id="my-visit" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="my-visit">My visit</h2>
<p>I visited the gallery on the morning of September 12th. After beginning my writing journey, I’ve been parsing through various local community calendars (<a href="https://radio.wpsu.org/community-calendar">thanks WPSU!</a>), Penn State art news postings, and official announcements looking for new ways I can immerse myself in the local art scene around Happy Valley. I went into the showing blind with no expectations or prior knowledge of the new faculty members’ work. It wasn’t until I arrived at the Zoller gallery that I learned who the new faculty members were. I also learned, upon arrival, that there is a gallery reception on the 24th of September. I think I’ll go back, hoping that I’ll be able to have a conversation with an artist or a few.</p>
</section>
<section id="and-other-stories" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="and-other-stories">… and other stories</h2>
<p>The installation that caught my attention immediately was displayed on the far wall of the gallery relative to the entrance.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><a href="photos\IMG_4654.JPEG" class="lightbox" data-gallery="quarto-lightbox-gallery-1" title="… and other stories"><img src="https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/sept12_24/photos/IMG_4654.JPEG" class="img-fluid figure-img" alt="… and other stories"></a></p>
<figcaption>… and other stories</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>I’m not well-versed in comic book canon, but I was drawn to this piece by Kumasi Barnett. At first, I thought these were genuine comic books. All of them, however, seem like interpretations of real comic book characters and series, but modified to say things like “The Amazing Black-Man” instead of “The Amazing Spider-Man.” After returning from the exhibit, I did some reading on this display, and the comic books are all hand-painted. In 2019, Barnett’s “The Amazing Black-Man” was housed at the Los Angeles-based contemporary art gallery <a href="https://www.lowellryanprojects.com/">Lowell Ryan Projects</a>. From the gallery’s <a href="https://www.lowellryanprojects.com/the-amazing-blackman">piece on this installation</a>, I learned that Barnett used real comic books, but painted over recognizable characters like Spider-Man and Captain America. Instead, Barnett reenvisions their heroes and villains with subjects like “Cash in America,” and “White Fright.”</p>
<div class="columns">
<div class="column" style="width:45%;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><a href="photos\IMG_4660.JPEG" class="lightbox" data-gallery="quarto-lightbox-gallery-2" title="White Fright"><img src="https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/sept12_24/photos/IMG_4660.JPEG" class="img-fluid figure-img" alt="White Fright"></a></p>
<figcaption>White Fright</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div><div class="column" style="width:10%;">
<!-- empty column to create gap -->
</div><div class="column" style="width:45%;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><a href="photos\IMG_4661.JPEG" class="lightbox" data-gallery="quarto-lightbox-gallery-3" title="America versus America"><img src="https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/sept12_24/photos/IMG_4661.JPEG" class="img-fluid figure-img" alt="America versus America"></a></p>
<figcaption>America versus America</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>From the previously mentioned 2019 article on this installation:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>A traditional comic book narrative is founded on a simple plot structure: there is a villain that the police cannot contain, and so a citizen superhero steps in to save the day. Barnett clearly complicates this narrative. In a genre filled with rigid tropes, his work is imbued with ambiguities: What kind of superhero is The Amazing Black-Man? In a society built on systemic racism, does his brown mask hide his identity or define it? Is his costume actually a costume? More importantly, what are his superpowers? How will he triumph over his foe?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This work raises many questions, perhaps some that I’d like to ask of Barnett now that he is a faculty member in the School of Visual Arts. <strong>I’ll certainly have to return for the reception.</strong></p>
</section>
<section id="some-other-photos" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="some-other-photos">Some other photos</h2>
<p>Take a moment to preview some of the other works I captured at the Zoller Gallery’s Panna Fresca:</p>
<div id="listing-listing-gallery" class="quarto-listing quarto-listing-container-custom">
<style type="text/css">
.grid-gallery {
  columns: 5 200px;
  column-gap: 0.5rem;
  width: 90%;
  margin: 0 auto;
}
.grid-item {
  width: 150px;
  margin: 0 0.5rem 0.5rem 0;
  display: inline-block;
  width: 100%;
  border-radius: 5px;
}
img.grid-item {
  width: 100%;
  transition: all .25s ease-in-out;
}
img.grid-item:hover {
  transform: scale(1.025);
}
</style>
<div class="grid-gallery">
<div>
<p><a href="../..\posts\sept12_24\photos\IMG_4654.JPEG" class="lightbox" data-gallery="quarto-grid-gallery"><img src="https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/sept12_24/photos/IMG_4654.JPEG" class="grid-item img-fluid" loading="lazy"></a></p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a href="../..\posts\sept12_24\photos\IMG_4655.JPEG" class="lightbox" data-gallery="quarto-grid-gallery"><img src="https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/sept12_24/photos/IMG_4655.JPEG" class="grid-item img-fluid" loading="lazy"></a></p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a href="../..\posts\sept12_24\photos\IMG_4657.JPEG" class="lightbox" data-gallery="quarto-grid-gallery"><img src="https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/sept12_24/photos/IMG_4657.JPEG" class="grid-item img-fluid" loading="lazy"></a></p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a href="../..\posts\sept12_24\photos\IMG_4658.JPEG" class="lightbox" data-gallery="quarto-grid-gallery"><img src="https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/sept12_24/photos/IMG_4658.JPEG" class="grid-item img-fluid" loading="lazy"></a></p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a href="../..\posts\sept12_24\photos\IMG_4659.JPEG" class="lightbox" data-gallery="quarto-grid-gallery"><img src="https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/sept12_24/photos/IMG_4659.JPEG" class="grid-item img-fluid" loading="lazy"></a></p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a href="../..\posts\sept12_24\photos\IMG_4660.JPEG" class="lightbox" data-gallery="quarto-grid-gallery"><img src="https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/sept12_24/photos/IMG_4660.JPEG" class="grid-item img-fluid" loading="lazy"></a></p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a href="../..\posts\sept12_24\photos\IMG_4661.JPEG" class="lightbox" data-gallery="quarto-grid-gallery"><img src="https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/sept12_24/photos/IMG_4661.JPEG" class="grid-item img-fluid" loading="lazy"></a></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="listing-no-matching d-none">
No matching items
</div>
</div>



</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Visual Arts</category>
  <category>On-Campus</category>
  <guid>https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/sept12_24/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/sept12_24/thumbnail.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Welcome to: The Arts in Happy Valley</title>
  <dc:creator>Andrew Ferguson</dc:creator>
  <link>https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/welcome/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<section id="welcome-to-the-arts-in-happy-valley" class="level1">
<h1>Welcome to: The Arts in Happy Valley</h1>
<section id="introductions" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introductions">Introductions</h2>
<p>Hey, it’s good to be here. My name’s Andrew. I live and work in Happy Valley, Pennsylvania, I love making websites, and I’m passionate about the arts. Hopefully, these three facts about me are evident, and are what brought you here.</p>
<p>While I didn’t attend Penn State, I’ve been around the area my whole life. Both of my parents are Nittany Lions, met here at University Park, got married in Eisenhower Chapel, and are now settled here for their <strong>well-deserved</strong> retirement.</p>
<p>In the arts, I’m most familiar with music. I studied Ethnomusicology in my time as an undergraduate student, which involved immersion in musical idioms from around the world. Presently, I am also a part-time graduate student studying Public Heritage and Museum Practice.</p>
</section>
<section id="purpose" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="purpose">Purpose</h2>
<p>My aims in starting this project are both internal and external. - Intrinsically, I want to motivate myself to engage with the plethora of local art in the Centre County region; it’s out there and I certainly want to be paying attention. I want to hone in on my own abilities as a writer and as a critical thinker about art. - Extrinsically, I want to motivate others to do the same. Join me in discovering all that Happy Valley has to offer.</p>
</section>
<section id="plan" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="plan">Plan</h2>
<p>I intend to publish one <em>digest</em>, weekly, on the various art and art-adjacent activities I’ve been engaged with - whether that’s an interview with a local band I’ve learned about lately, an account of a nearby gallery I visited, or even a seasonal update on the cocktail offerings at Chumley’s.</p>
<p>My first post (second if you count this inauguration) will be on the <strong>Bellefonte Museum of Art</strong>. Look for that article the week of September 16th. I’m looking forward to visiting and collecting my observations. I hope you look forward to reading.</p>
</section>
<section id="in-conversation" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="in-conversation">In Conversation</h2>
<p>At the bottom of this post, there is a comments section. Leave a comment if there is something around Happy Valley you think I should visit and write about. Or, leave a comment on the kinds of content you want to see me write about. I hope to start a conversation there.</p>
</section>
<section id="closing" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="closing">Closing</h2>
<p>I think art should be for everyone. While I am not an artist or a scholar of art by any means of the traditional definition, I plan to engage with the local art community in good faith, and I hope to inspire some readers to do the same.</p>
<p>-Andrew</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>meta</category>
  <guid>https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/welcome/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://happy-valley-arts.com/posts/welcome/thumbnail.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
